http://www.eaglemusicshop.com/content/privacy.htm

Visit our shop
Eagle Music Shop is based in the tranquil setting of Armitage Bridge, Huddersfield. We are a family business headed by seasoned musician Steve Noon. You will be made most welcome if you visit our shop & showrooms.
Read more and plan your visit to Eagle
Advice Topics
We're passionate about music, we're also highly experienced in all technical matters for the musical instruments we provide. In this section we share our knowledge to help you get the best out of your instrument.
Browse our Advice Topics
Buying Guides
We know that choosing the right instrument can be a difficult decision, so much choice and so many contributing factors to the right instrument for you. So here we provide our in depth knowledge to help your decision.
Browse our Buying Guides
Videos
Our video section features snippets from Eagle Music events, award presentations, instrument demonstrations and technical advice.
Browse our video section
BanjosBanjos4 String Banjos5 String Banjos6 String Guitar BanjoUke BanjosVintage Era BanjosUsed BanjosUsed Banjos (SOLD)Beginners Banjo PacksView All BanjosLeft Handed BanjosParts & AccessoriesParts & AccessoriesArmrestsBridgesCapos & SpikesCleaners & PolishesBracket Keys, Nuts & HooksDeering Banjo AccessoriesHeads & VellumsMetronomes (Electronic)Metronomes (Mechanical)MutesPitch PipesPicks & PlectrumsStandsStands (Music, Mic, Foot)StrapsString WindersTailpiecesTunersTuning PegsAmps, Pickups, Cables EtcAmps, Pickups, Cables EtcAmplifiersCablesEffects Pedals & Foot-switchesPickups & TransducersPre AmpsGig Bags & Hard CasesBooksBooksTutor BooksTutor Books5 String BanjoTenor BanjoMusic & SongMusic & Song5 String BanjoTenor BanjoDVD'sMusic CDsString SetsString Sets4 String Tenor5 String6 String Guitar BanjoSingle StringsGuitarsGuitarsAcoustic GuitarsElectro Acoustic GuitarsClassicalElectric GuitarsResonator GuitarsTravel GuitarsBanjo GuitarsLap Steel GuitarsBeginners Guitar PacksTenor GuitarsUsed GuitarsUsed Guitars (SOLD)View All GuitarsLeft Handed GuitarsAccessories for GuitarAccessories for GuitarCaposCleaners & PolishesEnd Pins & Bridge PinsMachine Heads / TunersMetronomes (Electronic)Metronomes (Mechanical)Miscellaneous AccessoriesNail ClothPitch PipesPicks & Plectrums etcPicks & Plectrums etcGuitar Picks & PlectrumsFinger PicksThumb PicksStandsStands (Music, Mic, Foot)Steels & SlidesString WindersStrapsTunersAmps, Pickups, Cables EtcAmps, Pickups, Cables EtcAmplifiersCablesEffects Pedals & Foot-SwitchesMicrophones (Hand Held)Pickups & TransducersPre AmpsGig Bags & Hard CasesGig Bags & Hard CasesGig BagsHard CasesBooksBooksTutor & ChordMaintenanceMusic & SongDVD'sMusic CDsString SetsString SetsAcoustic GuitarBass GuitarClassical GuitarElectric GuitarSingle StringsMandolin &BouzoukiMandolin &BouzoukiMandolinsOctave MandolasBouzoukisLeft Handed MandolinsLeft Handed BouzoukisCitternsBeginners Packs for Mandolin FamilyUsed Mandolins & BouzoukisUsed Mandolins & Bouzoukis (Sold)View All Mandolin FamilyAccessories for MandolinAccessories for MandolinBridges & TailpiecesCaposCleaners & PolishesMachine Heads / TunersMetronomes (Electronic)Metronomes (Mechanical)Nail ClothPitch PipesPicks & PlectrumsPicks & PlectrumsFlat Picks & PlectrumsFinger PicksThumb PicksStandsStands (Music, Mic, Foot)String WindersStrapsTunersAmps, Pickups, Cables EtcAmps, Pickups, Cables EtcAmplifiersCablesEffects Pedals & Foot-switchesPickups & TransducersPre AmpsGig Bags & Hard CasesBooksBooksBouzouki TutorMandolin TutorMandolin Music & SongMandolin DVD'sMusic CDsBouzouki DVD'sString SetsString SetsBouzoukiCitternMandolin, Octave Mandola, Mando Guitar EtcSingle StringsUkuleleUkuleleSoprano UkeConcert UkeTenor UkeBaritone UkeBanjo UkeBeginners Ukulele PacksUsed UkesUsed Ukes (SOLD)View All UkulelesAccessories for UkuleleAccessories for UkuleleCaposCleaners & PolishesMachine Heads / TunersMetronomes (Electronic)Metronomes (Mechanical)Miscellaneous AccessoriesPitch PipesPlectrums & Thumb PicksUkulele StandsStrapsString WindersTunersPickups & TransducersBooksBooksTutorMusic & SongDVD'sGig Bags & Hard CasesMusic CDsStringsHarmonicaHarmonicaDiatonic HarmonicasChromatic HarmonicasTremolo & Octave HarmonicasBeginners Harmonica PacksView All HarmonicasAccessories for HarmonicaAccessories for HarmonicaHarnessesReed Plates & CombsStands (Music, Mic, Foot)ToolkitsPickups & TransducersGig Bags & CasesBooksBooksTutorMusic & SongDVD'sMusic CDsNovelties / BadgesSqueezeboxSqueezeboxButton AccordionConcertinaMelodeonPiano AccordionBeginners Squeezebox PacksUsed SqueezeboxesView All SqueezeboxesStrapsGig Bags & Hard CasesPickups & TransducersBooksBooksTutorTutorPiano AccordionButton AccordionConcertinaMelodeonMusic & SongMusic & SongPiano AccordionButton AccordionConcertinaMelodeonDVD'sDVD'sPiano AccordionButton AccordionConcertinaMelodeonMusic CDsMusic CDsPiano AccordionButton AccordionConcertinaMelodeonBodhran &PercussionBodhran &PercussionBodhransUsed BodhransPercussion for FunWorld PercussionBodhran BeatersBodhran Gig BagsBooksBooksBodhran TutorPercussion TutorBodhran & Percussion DVD'sFlute &WhistleFlute &WhistleFlutesHigh whistles | Tin WhistlesLow WhistlesStarter PacksFlute & Whistle StandsFlute & Whistle Gig BagsBooksBooksTutorTutorFluteTin WhistleMusic & SongMusic & SongFluteTin WhistleMusic CDs for Irish Flute / WhistlePickups & TransducersFlute DVD'sTin Whistle DVD'sHarps &DulcimersHarps &DulcimersHarps & DulcimersAutoharpsBooksBooksTutorTutorAppalachian DulcimerHammered DulcimerAutoharpHarpMusic & SongMusic & SongAppalachian DulcimerHammered DulcimerHarpMusic CDs for HarpDulcimer DVD'sViolinViolinElectric ViolinViolin OutfitsViolin Starter PacksUsed ViolinsAccessories for ViolinAccessories for ViolinBowsBridgesCare, Cleaners, PolishesPitch PipesPitch PipesShoulder Rests & Chin RestsStandsTailpieces, Tailguts, End Pins, Mutes & Fine TunersTuning PegsPickups & TransducersGig Bags & Hard CasesBooksBooksTutorMusic & SongViolin DVD'sIrish Fiddle Music CDsViolin StringsBooksBooksBy Country of Musical OriginBy Country of Musical OriginAmericanEnglish Music BooksEnglish Song BooksEuropeanIrish Music BooksIrish Song BooksScottish Music BooksScottish Song BooksWelshTutor Books by InstrumentTutor Books by InstrumentAccordion - ButtonAccordion - PianoAutoharp5 String BanjoTenor BanjoBassBodhranBouzoukiConcertinaAppalachian DulcimerHammered DulcimerFiddleFluteGuitar Maintenance BooksGuitar - Tutor & ChordHarmonicaHarpMandolinMelodeonOcarinaPercussionPianoPipingRecorderTin WhistleUkuleleMusic & Song Books by InstrumentMusic & Song Books by InstrumentAccordion - ButtonAccordion - Piano5 String BanjoTenor BanjoConcertinaDulcimer - AppalachianHammered DulcimerFiddleFluteGuitarHarmonicaHarpMandolinMelodeonPianoPipingRecorderTin WhistleUkuleleMiscellaneous & ChildrensReference booksChristmasDVD / CDMusic / TutorDVD / CDMusic / TutorRecorded CDs by InstrumentRecorded CDs by InstrumentAccordion - PianoAccordion - Irish ButtonBanjo - 5 StringBanjo - TenorConcertinaFiddleFlute & WhistleGuitarHarmonicaHarpMandolin FamilyFiddle - IrishMelodeonPiping BandsPiping SoloRecorded CDs by GenreRecorded CDs by GenreCajunCeltic CompilationCeltic MoodsCountry & BluegrassEnglish Music & SongGaelicIrish CompilationIrish CountryIrish DanceIrish Group / BandIrish InstrumentalIrish PipingIrish SingingPeriod MusicScottish DanceScottish MusicScottish SongScottish Traditional BandWorld MusicTutor DVD by InstrumentTutor DVD by InstrumentAccordion - PianoAccordion - Irish ButtonBanjoBodhranBouzoukiConcertinaDulcimerFiddleFluteGuitarHarmonicaMandolinMelodeonMiscellaneousBongosRecorderTin WhistleUkuleleClearanceClearanceStringed InstrumentsOther InstrumentsGig Bags & CasesMiscellaneousNovelties& GiftsNovelties& GiftsGifts for ChildrenNovelties - Badges EtcChristmasBrandsOur BrandsAdmiraBushmanClareenCrafterDavidsonDeeringDeering VegaEastmanErin MandolinsFaithFideliusGold ToneHeringHohnerHuberImuaKalaKamakaLeader Banjo CoMartinNechvilleOhanaOmeOzarkPruchaSaltarelleSeydelSigma GuitarsStellingSuzukiTanglewoodWeberBrowse our full range of brandsBuying GuidesAdvice TopicsVideosMy AccountVisitContact UsAbout UsCurrencyCurrency£ GBP$ USD€ EUR$ AUDkr DKK
Search
Our Showroom Is Open! - Visits By Appointment Only. See latest COVID-19 info here
Home
» Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
Menu
Company Information
About Us
Read our blog
Contact Us
Introduction
We are committed to protecting the privacy of our site visitors and customers. We fully appreciate and respect the importance of your privacy. We will treat all your personal information as confidential (although we reserve the right to disclose this information in the circumstances set out below). This Privacy Notice explains the type of personal data we may collect, why we need it and how we keep it safe.
It is likely that we’ll need to update this Privacy Notice from time to time, please refer to this notice at your convenience, we’ll notify you of any significant changes.
Version 24/5/2018
1. Controller
Eagle Music Shop, 1 St Pauls House, Brooke’s Mill,
Armitage Bridge, Huddersfield, HD4 7NR, United Kingdom
+44 1484 661660
(hereafter ”we”)
2. When do we collect your personal data?
There are a number of areas of our website where we will collect your personal data, as follows:
When you make a purchase through our website as a guest or registered user
When you use the contact form on our contact us page
When you sign up as a registered user on our website
When you place an enquiry through our website
When you place a price match enquiry through our website
When you use the live chat facility on our website
When you sign up for our newsletter
When you comment on a blog article
3. What sort of personal data do we collect?
If shopping on our website, we will collect your name, email, telephone, delivery and billing address, IP address (Your IP address may vary unless you have a fixed IP address).
Your order history
Your consent choices
Details of your visits and activity on our website
Information gathered by the use of cookies in your web browser. Learn more about how we use cookies here.
4. Use of Cookies
We use cookies to keep track of your current shopping session to personalise your experience and so that you may retrieve your shopping basket at any time; if you do not accept cookies, you will be unable to use this website for shopping purposes. Our site cannot function properly without the use of cookies. Read more about how we use cookies here.
5. How and why do we use your personal data?
We are committed to providing you with a great customer experience, in order to achieve this, we must collect your personal data. Any data we collect is of legitimate interest and is so allowed by the data privacy law. This document outlines the data that is collected through our website.
Please be aware that if you do not wish to share your personal data with us, or refuse certain contact permissions, we are likely to not be able to offer our service to you. For example, you will not be able to place an order through our website.
Here is a list of reasons how and why we use your personal data:
So that you can place an order through our website. If we don’t collect your personal data, such as your name and address, we won’t be able to process your order.
To keep you informed about the status of your order via transactional emails.
To respond to order queries, returns, refunds, complaints etc. We need to keep a history of your personal data so that we can identify you and your order/enquiry history.
To pass to a third party delivery provider. We need to deliver your product through a third party delivery provider, so we must pass your address details to them.
To contact you about special offers, promotions and latest news.
To improve the user experience of our website by analyzing your website activity.
To provide you with a personalized user experience by analyzing your website activity.
To send you personalized emails based on your user activity and purchase history.
To send you invitations to write a review of your order and products purchased.
6. Who do we share your personal data with and why?
There are a number of circumstances that mean we must share your personal data with trusted third parties. We will not share your information for marketing purposes with companies outside of our organization. We only share your data so that we can facilitate your order and so that we can improve the website user experience on the whole. We only share to those whereby it is directly related to the functionality and marketing of our own website/business.
Here is a list of whom and why we share your data:-
SagePay - this is our primary payment gateway, we must pass them your personal details to take payment.
Data shared: name, email, address, credit card, identification details
PayPal - this is our secondary payment gateway, we must pass them your personal details to take payment.
Data shared: name, email, address, identification details
Royal Mail, ParcelForce, DPD - we need to pass your details to our delivery partner so that your goods can be delivered.
Data shared: name, phone, email, address
OMNI Capital - if you apply for finance, we need to pass your personal details to our finance provider.
Data shared: name, email, address
eKomi - so that we can send customer and product review requests to our customers.
Data shared: name, email, order item details
LiveChat Inc - so that we can offer our customers a facility to chat with us other than by phone, email.
Data shared: name, email, identification details such as IP address
Google - so that we can understand our website performance and make improvements
Data shared: Anonymized identification details
Nextopia - so that we can improve the quality of our customers’ website searches
Data shared: Identification details such as IP address
7. Your consent to us using your data
During checkout, providing your email address as part of the purchase procedure is not considered consent to use that email for any email marketing purposes and as such the only communication you will receive will be for transactional purposes only.
On various pages on our site, including pages within the checkout flow, you can tick boxes in forms to consent (opt-in) to us contacting you for purposes other than transactional, such as marketing emails, sms and postal material.
If we send you email marketing, there will be a link on the email so that you can easily unsubscribe. You can also update your consent options by logging in to your account and clicking the consent options link.
8. How long do we keep your data?
We need to retain your personal data for as long as you are a customer of ours, this ensures that both ourselves and you, the customer, can view your order history. Your order history is vital should any issues arise with a past purchase, we also use your order history to offer you a better and more personalized user experience. We store the personal data for as long as is necessary considering the purpose of the processing. We also need to retain your data for accounting reasons such as tax, audits etc.
9. How do you manage your communication preferences?
There are a number of ways you can stop direct marketing communications from us:
When logged in to your account, you can go to the page called ‘Communication Preferences’, here you can see the choices you have previously made. From here, you can easily opt-in or opt-out at a granular level
When we send email marketing, there will be a link at the footer of the email that you can click to easily unsubscribe to that mailing list. This will stop any further emails from that particular list
You can write to us as per the contact details in section 14.
10. How do you access the information we hold about you?
You have the right to request access to the personal data we hold about you, this is in the form of your customer record and order history, if you have an account, you can browse this information on our website.
If you would like a copy of that information, you can write to as per the contact details in section 14. Within reason, this information can be provided free of charge.
11. How do we protect your personal data?
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect.
12. What are your rights to erasure?
Under certain circumstances, you have the right to have your personal data to be erased. This would be a rare circumstance as we have legitimate reason to keep your data as per the reasons written in this policy.
We can review your request on an individual basis, to do this, you can write to us as per the contact details in section 14 below.
13. Changes to our privacy policy
Should we make amendments to this privacy policy we will place the amended statement on our website, with an indication of the amendment date. If the amendments are significant, we may also inform you about this by other means, for example by sending an email or placing a bulletin on our homepage. We recommend that you regularly visit our webpage and notice possible amendments to this privacy policy, review these privacy protection principles from time to time to ensure you are aware of any amendments made.
14. Who do I contact for further information
All contacts and requests concerning this privacy policy must be submitted in writing or in person to the person mentioned below:
Data Protection Coordinator
Eagle Music Shop, 1 St Pauls House, Brooke’s Mill, Armitage Bridge, Huddersfield, HD4 7NR.
Selected review
by KEN DOLAN on 24/03/2020 21:34:00
Great response and classy product. You’ve got to love Eagle Music xx
Read more
We use cookies
By continuing to browse the site you are agreeing to our use of cookies. More information
Continue
Close
Item(s) added to your compare list
Compare now
